Pauline Frederick Papers, 1917-1990
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- Series IV. PHOTOGRAPHS
  - Professional Activities, [See Appendix for alphabetical list of photos of individuals]
    - Speeches and events
      - Puerto Rico, 1962 (Box 49, Folder 10)
      - 1960-73 (Box 49, Folder 11-14)
      - 1975, undated (Box 50, Folder 1-2)
    - Writings: "Women in Diplomacy," 1931-32 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Awards, 1951-81, undated (Box 50, Folder 4-5)
    - Honorary degrees, 1956-85 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous notables, 1962, 1973, undated (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Personal Activities
    - Childhood, c. 1908, undated (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Education
      - Thomas A. Edison Junior High School (Harrisburg, PA), 1923, undated (Box 51, Folder 2)
      - American University, 1927-30, undated (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Family, 1935, undated (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Dogs, 1952, undated (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Vacations, 1953-60, undated (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous, 1920s-80 s (Box 51, Folder 7-8)
- SERIES V. AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS, [NOTE: Most of these AV materials have been digitized and are accessible on the Smith College website (on campus only). Digital files are also available for purchase. Contact us for more information]
  - Phonograph Records (12 inch)
    - ABC, [see also PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES, ABC]
      - News broadcasts, 1947-51 (5 discs) (Box 52)
      - Programs
        - "Speaking Frankly," (Hon. James F. Byrnes), 14 and 18 Oct 1947 (2 discs) (Box 52)
        - "Women in the News," 18 Apr 1952 (2 discs) (Box 52)
      - Interviews
        - Randolph Churchill, 30 Sep 1946 (1 disc) (Box 52)
        - Gordon Dean, 28 Aug 1951 (1 disc) (Box 52)
      - Special coverage
        - WJTN inauguration, 24 Oct 1947 (2 discs) (Box 52)
        - Royal wedding, 20 Nov 1947 (3 discs) (Box 52)
        - Korea, 14 Jul 1950 (2 discs) (Box 52)
      - Miscellaneous
        - BBC Talk for ABC, 9 May 1952 and 5 Jun 1962 (3 discs) (Box 52)
        - "H.E. Europe Intr. P. Frederick: short lengths in Paris interviewing [Mr./Mrs. Sturtevant?]" (1 disc) (Box 52)
    - NBC, [see also PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES, NBC]
      - News broadcasts
        - Opening of UN Charter Conference in San Francisco, 25 Apr 1945 (1 disc) (Box 52)
        - UN commentary, 26 Apr 1956 (2 discs) (Box 52)
      - Program: "Listen to the Witness," 18 Sep 1954 (2 discs) (Box 52)
      - Interview (unidentified), 19 May 1959 (2 discs) (Box 52)
      - Awards and appearances, BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL, Awards]
        - Peabody Award, 23 Apr 1955 (2 discs) (Box 52)
        - "Helen Hall Show" ("Broadcast Woman of the Year" and "Pauline Frederick"), undated (4 discs) (Box 52)
      - Unidentified (2 discs) (Box 52)
  - Phonograph Records (16 inch)
    - ABC, [see also PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES, ABC]
      - "Interview of Pauline Frederick," 18 Jul 1946 (Box 53)
      - "A Woman Views the News," Pauline Frederick and Marshall Shantz, 20 Jul 1946 (Box 53)
      - Interview with James F. Byrnes, by Pauline Frederick, 20 Oct 1947 (Box 53)
      - "American Delegation Round Table," 13 Sep 1948 (1 disc) [note on sleeve, "Mrs. Roosevelt"] (Box 53)
      - "DP Interview, Pauline Frederick," 31 Oct 1948 (1 disc) (Box 53)
      - "Pauline Frederick," 31 May and 1 Jun 1949 (2 discs) (Box 53)
      - "Consent of the Governed," 4 Jul 1949 (1 disc) (Box 53)
      - "Puerto Rico Recording," 8 Dec 1949 (1 disc) (Box 53)
      - "Berlin," 2 Apr 1950 (1 disc) (Box 53)
      - "Vacation Time," 9 Apr 1950 (1 disc) (Box 53)
      - "Lake Success," 25 Jun 1950 (1 disc) (Box 53)
      - UN session, 3 Jan 1951 (2 discs) (Box 53)
      - "Headline Edition," undated (1 disc) (Box 53)
    - NBC: Dupont Award presentation, 26 Mar 1954 (2 discs), [see also BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL, Awards] (Box 53)
    - Unidentified (3 discs) (Box 53)
  - Cassette Tapes, [An asterisk denotes cassettes that are duplicates of reel-to-reel tapes in boxes 57-59.]
    - ABC, [see also PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES, ABC]
      - Interview: Lord [Jowitt], Lord Chancellor of England on British Elections-- Oct. 26, 20 Sep 1951 (1 tape) * (Box 54)
      - Special coverage: "Bela Belassa resignation from Hungarian Consul General," 8 Feb 1949 (1 tape) * (Box 54)
    - NBC, [see also PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITES, NBC]
      - News broadcasts
        - 1953-55 (7 tapes) (Box 54)
        - "About Hammarskjold, Heart of the News," 30 Aug 1956 (1 tape) * (Box 54)
      - Programs
        - "Nite Line," 1958-59 (4 tapes) * (Box 54)
        - "Today Show"
          - 1959-63 (5 tapes) * (Box 54)
          - 1970-73 (4 tapes) * (Box 55)
        - "What Risk Retaliation?," 4 Mar 1954 (2 tapes) * (Box 55)
        - "USSR and UN, 18 Feb 1959 (1 tape) * (Box 55)
        - ["Emphasis"]: "Women's Help in S[outh] A[merica]," 21 Jun 1961 (1 tape)* (Box 55)
      - Interviews
        - Soviet Foreign Minister V.M. Molotov upon arrival in San Francisco, 18 Jun 1955 (1 tape) * (Box 55)
        - Press conference with Dag Hammarskjold, about to go to the Middle East, 5 Apr 1956 (1 tape) * (Box 55)
        - Henry Cabot Lodge, 19 Sep 1959 (1 tape) * (Box 55)
        - [Mohammed H.] El-Zayyat on "Nightly, Sunday Night," 6 Sep 1970 (1 tape) * (Box 55)
        - [Golda Meir and El Farra of Jordan], 30 Oct 1970 (1 tape) (Box 55)
        - Ambassador [Arthur] Goldberg, 6 July ? (1 tape) * (Box 55)
    - National Public Radio, [see also PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES, NPR]
      - Programs
        - "Options": "Henry Kissinger discussed by 4 people," [interviewed by P.F.], 14 Oct 1976 (1 tape) * (Box 55)
        - "All Things Considered"
          - "Commentaries," 1979 (1 tape) * (Box 55)
          - [Henry] Kissinger, undated (1 tape) * (Box 55)
      - Promotion: "This Is NPR," Oct 1976 (1 tape) (Box 55)
      - Interviews
        - [Nelson?] Rockefeller, 23 Jun 1973 (1 tape) * (Box 55)
        - "P. Frederick and A[nthony] Lewis with UN Ambassador Andrew Young," 1978 (1 tape) * (Box 56)
    - Miscellaneous activities, [see also PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES, Other activities]
      - Fidel Castro, U[nited] N[ations] Correspondents Association, 21 Apr ? (2 tapes) * (Box 56)
      - USSR luncheon, 17 Apr 1963 (includes speech by [Nikolai Fedorenko]) (2 tapes) * (Box 56)
      - "Alumni Alert" (interview of P. Frederick), Feb 1970 (1 tape) * (Box 56)
      - "Foreign Policy Luncheon," 6 Jan 1972 (1 tape) * (Box 56)
    - Speeches, [see also PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITES, Speeches and events]
      - "World Survival Through U.N. Reform," [Los Angeles ?], May 1980 (1 tape) (Box 56)
      - Rotary dinner, 5 Feb 1950 (introduced by Milton Soffer) (1 tape) * (Box 56)
      - Farm and Home Group, Louisiana State University, 10 Aug 1954 (1 tape) * (Box 56)
      - "The Blasphemy of Independence," Kent State University, 18 Apr 1974 (1 tape) * (Box 56)
    - Biography
      - P. Frederick interviewed by Celeste Holm, 28 May 1962 (1 tape) * (Box 56)
      - Wedding of Pauline Frederick and Charles Robbins, 31 Mar 1969 (2 tapes) * (Box 56)
      - "Molly Teagle Show" (about P. Frederick), undated (1 tape) * (Box 56)
      - P. Frederick interviewed by unidentified individual, undated (1 tape) * (Box 56)
    - Awards, [see also BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL, Awards]
      - Carr Van Anda Award, acceptance speech, University of Ohio, Athens, School of Journalism, 7 May 1971 (1 tape) *, [see also OVERSIZE MATERIAL] (Box 56)
      - Paul White Award reception and banquet, undated (1 tape) (Box 56)
  - Reel-to-reel Tapes, [A plus sign denotes reel-to-reel tapes that have cassetteduplicates in boxes 54-56.]
    - ABC, [see also PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES, ABC]
      - News broadcasts, 1953-54 (5 tapes) (Box 57)
      - Interview: Lord [Jowitt], Lord Chancellor of England, on British elections-- Oct 26, 20 Sep 1951 (1 tape) + (Box 57)
      - Special coverage: Bela Belassa resignation from Hungarian Consul General, 8 Feb 1949 (1 tape) + (Box 57)
    - NBC, [see also PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES, NBC]
      - News broadcasts
        - UN and China, 12 Dec 1954, 21 Jan1955 (2 tapes) + (Box 57)
        - "About Hammarskjold, Heart of the News," 30 Aug 1956 (1 tape) + (Box 57)
      - Programs
        - "Nite Line," 1958-59 (4 tapes) + (Box 57)
        - "Today Show," 1959-73 (10 tapes) + (Box 57)
        - "What Risk Retaliation?," 4 Mar 1954 (2 tapes) + (Box 58)
        - "USSR and UN," 18 Feb 1959 (1 tape) + (Box 58)
        - ["Emphasis"]: "Women's Help in South America," 21 Jun 1961 (1 tape)+ (Box 58)
      - Interviews
        - Soviet Foreign Minister V.M. Molotov [upon arrival in San Francisco], 18 Jun 1955 (1 tape) (Box 58)
        - Press conference of Dag Hammarskjold, about to go to the Middle East, 5 Apr 1956 (1 tape) + (Box 58)
        - Henry Cabot Lodge, 19 Sep 1959 (1 tape) + (Box 58)
        - United Nations [?], 14 Oct 1960 (1 tape) + (Box 58)
        - [Mohammed H.] El-Zayyat, "Nightly, Sunday Night," 6 Sep 1970 (1 tape) + (Box 58)
        - Ambassador [Arthur] Goldberg, 6 Jul ? (1 tape) + (Box 58)
        - Unidentified, "Moscow," 27 Aug [?] (1 tape) (Box 58)
    - National Public Radio, [see also PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES, NPR]
      - Programs
        - "Options": "Henry Kissinger discussed by four people, interviewed by P.F.," 14 Oct 1976 (1 tape) + (Box 58)
        - "All Things Considered"
          - "Commentaries," 1979 (1 tape) + (Box 58)
          - [Henry] Kissinger, undated (1 tape) + (Box 58)
      - Interviews
        - [Nelson?] Rockefeller, 23 Jun 1977 (1 tape) + (Box 58)
        - "P. F[rederick] and Anthony Lewis with UN Ambassador Andrew Young," 1978 (1 tape) + (Box 58)
    - Miscellaneous activities, [see also PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITES, Other activities]
      - Fidel Castro, United Nations Correspondents Association, 21 Apr ? (2 tapes) + (Box 58)
      - USSR luncheon, 17 Apr 1963 (includes speech by [Nikolai Fedorenko]) (2 tapes) + (Box 58)
      - "Alumni Alert" (interview of P.Frederick), Feb 1970 (1 tape) + (Box 58)
      - "Foreign policy luncheon," 6 Jan 1972 (1 tape) + (Box 58)
    - Speeches, [see also PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES, Speeches and events]
      - Rotary dinner, 5 Feb 1950 (introduced by Milton Soffer) (2 tapes) + (Box 59)
      - Farm and Home Group, Louisiana State University, 10 Aug 1954 (2 tapes) + (Box 59)
      - "The Blasphemy of Independence," Kent State University, 18 Apr 1974 (1 tape) + (Box 59)
    - Biography
      - P. Frederick interviewed by Celeste Holm, 28 May 1962 (1 tape) + (Box 59)
      - Wedding of Pauline Frederick and Charles Robbins, 31 Mar 1969 +
        - unedited (2 tapes) (Box 59)
        - edited (1 tape) (Box 59)
      - "Molly Teagle Show" (about P. Frederick), undated (1 tape) + (Box 59)
      - P. Frederick interviewed by unidentified individual, undated (1 tape) (Box 59)
    - Awards: Carr Van Anda Award, acceptance speech, University of Ohio, Athens, School of Journalism, 7 May 1971 (1 tape) +, [see also BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL, Awards; OVERSIZE MATERIALS] (Box 59)
    - Miscellaneous
      - P. Frederick interviewed by unidentified individual, undated (1 tape)+ (Box 59)
      - "Harry E. Hawkenson's questions to the President," undated (1 tape) (Box 59)
      - Unidentified (Box 59)
  - Films
    - Awards, [see also BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL, Awards]
      - duPont, 26 Mar 1954, (2 films, 16 mm., black and white) (Box 59)
      - Peabody, 20 April 1955 (16 mm., black and white) (Box 59)
      - McCall's Mike, Boston, 28 April 1956 (35mm., black and white) (Box 59)
    - U.S.-Japan Atomic Industrial Forums: Joint Conference on Nuclear Power, Dec 1961 (2 films, 8 mm., color, no sound) (Box 59)
    - "Conn. Public TV, Sep 1962 " (8 mm.) (Box 59)
    - WDSU-TV broadcast, 3 May 1967 (16 mm., color) (Box 59)
    - Andrei Gromyko press conference, undated (16 mm., black and white) (Box 59)
    - Dag Hammarskjold, interviewed by P. Frederick, undated (16 mm., black and white, no sound) (Box 59)
- Series VI. OVERSIZE MATERIALS
  - "Agreement Between the Government of the United States of America and the Government of Canada Relating to the Establishment of the Roosevelt Campobello International ark," 22 Jan 1964 1945-77, undated (Box 60)
  - Poster: "Come and meet Pauline Frederick...Guest Speaker, 50th Anniversary commemoration of Red Cross service to military families," 7 Nov [?] (Box 60)
  - Awards, [see also BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL, Awards; AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS]
    - U.S.A. Air Forces Rest Center, Capri, Italy, 1945 (Box 60)
    - International House Program, State Teachers College, Jacksonville, AL, Honorary Member, 19 Jul 1951 (Box 60)
    - McCall's Mike, 1955 (Box 60)
    - The American Association for the United Nations, 21 Nov 1960 (Box 60)
    - Commonwealth of Kentucky, commissioned a Kentucky Colonel, 15 Aug 1961, 13 Apr 1966 (Box 60)
    - The New York City Professional Chapter of Sigma Delta Chi, certificate of Meritorious Achievement, 11 May 1962 (Box 60)
    - Kansas City, MO, Honorary Citizen, 12 May 1962 (Box 60)
    - People-to-people, Citation, 12 May 1962 (Box 60)
    - Fort Worth, TX, Honorary Citizen, 23 Oct 1964 (Box 60)
    - Pennsylvania Award for Excellence, Journalism, 1966 (Box 60)
    - YWCA of Philadelphia, Centennial Medal, 29 Oct 1969 (Box 60)
    - The School of Journalism of Ohio University (Athens), Carr Van Anda Award, 1971 (Box 60)
    - The Great Navy of the State of Nebraska, Admiral, 16 Jan 1973 (Box 60)
    - State of Connecticut, for "continuing work and contributions in the fields of Peace, Equality and Development, 18 Jan 1976 (Box 60)
    - The City of Louisville, Ambassador of Good Will, 26 Apr ? (Box 60)
  - Honorary degrees, [see also BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL, Honorary Degrees]
    - Lycoming College, 3 Jun 1956 (Box 60)
    - Ohio University, 6 Jun 1965 (Box 60)
    - University of Portland, 16 Feb 1977 (Box 60)
  - Photographs
    - P. Frederick, mostly portraits, 1947-63, undated (7) (Box 60)
    - David Sarnoff, 1958 (1) (Box 60)
    - Poster: advertisement for NBC news with photos of news staff (59 men and P.F.), undated (Map-case flat file)